hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast where I help
coaches and course graders scale their
businesses reach more clients and make
more money online now today I wanna wait
just a second and just pause how do I
actually pronounce your name it's Leila
Rose I had a feeling that I was missing
that's okay it doesn't matter people
call you Jeremy Leela Leela Leela Z Lila
zebra Lila zeros you have to put the Z
in because there's an there's other
people with the same name so okay all
right
hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jeremy
microkowski and on this podcast I help
coaches mentors course creators scale
their business get more clients make
more money and ultimately live the life
that they've always dreamed of today I
have a special guest Leela Z Rose she
helps people tap into the genius that's
inside of them and accomplish what seems
to be the impossible for most people she
makes it very simple and very practical
for them to go after their dreams and
create Magic and truly what she's been
able to do with her clients and the
people she's worked with is magical
Leela welcome to the podcast thank you
Jeremy I'm so happy to be here
so you and I were talking just a little
bit before about the the journey that
coaches go on mentors trainers and
you're a coach you're a consultant
um the people who listen to this podcast
are coaches Consultants mentors and the
the sort of the the fear of the unknown
is one of the biggest things when it
comes to stepping out and doing
something is what stops people but
before we go into that tell tell the
audience a little bit about yourself a
little bit about your background and how
you got into doing what you're doing
sure
um well I actually started in theater
and uh then um ended up in television
and I co-created to animated series and
ended up working with incredibly
talented people and I think the greatest
moment of my life was when a producer
said you know thanks to your ideas I've
been employed for seven years and I mean
is it is there anything better than that
there's nothing better than knowing yeah
and that's what creative people do
that's what genius does it it lights the
flame so that other people can also
benefit
um even in La I you know met an actor
for lunch that someone said I should
meet and it turned out uh he had voiced
on the show that I'd worked on so it's
okay yeah that's the thing it's lighting
that flame and I've also you know been
the kind of person I spot genius
um you know when I was casting for
television there are people that I open
doors for
um who didn't get auditions because they
were rejected early on but I'd see them
in a you know in an acting class us and
I'd be like wow we have to get that
person in and they'd get the role that
they might have been rejected for before
because they weren't being seen
so the whole idea of being seen letting
genius be seen
having your Genius out there is such a
huge thing and I've been a passionate
advocate for that and so just over the
years working with writers producers
directors like just working with people
and opening doors coaching and you know
it just happens organically when you're
in a creative community
now before we go to this I just want to
pause for everybody here you might be
saying wow like
I'm not at the level of like who Leela
works with and like is this really
something that I'm going to glean
knowledge and wisdom from I'm just
starting out in a coaching business
here's the thing I believe that
everybody has unique genius inside of
them
and that every coach or course creator
has a story that needs to be told but
the truth is when we think about putting
our stories out there there's a risk
right we don't know how it's going to
turn out we don't know how it's going to
be reacted to we don't know how people
are going to take it understand or
misunderstand it and so what ends up
stopping a lot of people is they they
want to put themselves out there they
have an idea
but they're waiting for certainty
to move forward and they and they don't
want to be criticized by people they're
even possibly afraid of backlash people
not liking them they don't want to make
mistakes
they might have a a spirit of Excellence
but then they beat themselves up when
they don't reach that and so what would
you just say to encourage somebody who's
dealing with this I guess you could say
performance anxiety when it comes to
coaching when it comes to putting their
business out there they want to do great
things but they're they're waiting until
they feel ready to do so
well you know I've supported in the
sense of like being a dream facilitator
that's how I like to look at it uh for
people from all over the world and that
includes refugees immigrants people in
I.T like I've really supported people at
every possible level that you can
imagine of The Human Experience when it
comes to trying to achieve a dream
and the number one thing I just I've
discovered and it's something that I
think um you know you just organically
do in how you coach
if you pull yourself out of the your
identity as being a small thing and
perceive yourself as the protagonist and
hero of your story not an extra in your
own story
that creates a completely different
approach and mindset yes and then you
understand you're in a Hero Journey
every single obstacle is like Luke
Skywalker or Harry Potter or you know
um Wonder Woman you're not just an
average person walking around trying to
make something happen your dreams and
goals have a ripple effect to all the
people you love that you're trying to
support with your success because we all
have that right whether it's an
immediate family or a group of friends I
have friends that are highly creative
that don't get to express their
creativity because of their financial
situation so dreams are usually bigger
than you anyway so if you stop
perceiving yourself as a small person
buffeted by all these forces arrayed
against you and realize that's exactly
what Heroes deal with yeah and start
perceiving yourself that way and
identifying as the hero not the extra
your whole being starts to change in the
way that you approach every opportunity
and obstacle
and and to that let me ask you this
because there's
there's people that they're just like I
I hear you Leela but
I've never done anything you've done so
much like I'm a nobody
and and and they feel like like they're
like but they have a message they want
to help people but they're just they're
just stuck
feeling like what can I do
and so is there what would you say to
speak to that because again I agree with
what you said
but a lot of people their the evidence
in their life doesn't point to that
reality and so a lot of people are like
well I want to be a realist like I'm I'm
a nobody
and so
how how do you help people kind of see
that they're not just a nobody that they
actually have a lot to offer and that
inside of every single person I believe
every single person listening to this
podcast can impact
thousands and tens of thousands of lives
but maybe they just don't see it yet
well I think I I think not seeing it yet
is common but you know I had a friend
who ended up on set as an extra
and um uh he told me all excited because
the director spotted him and gave him a
line
and he said I've got a line I've got a
line and I you know I think to myself
why not just give yourself a line
you know what what is it you want to say
what sentence if you had one sentence to
say to people what what would that be
you've just you've just elevated
yourself from extra to to you know actor
on set right and so I think what happens
with people we have a huge investment
in false modesty because I really
believe anyone that has a dream deep
down really deep down has that dream
Because deep down they actually do
believe they can achieve it but they
have so many internalized
don't be conceited
um you know don't don't
um they have so much internalized shame
around the idea of success around the
idea of of being out there when I say be
out there like I'm an introvert I write
books like right you know I'm often
behind the scenes I'm not I'm not
necessarily I've been in front of the
camera I've been behind the camera but
I'm often happiest alone writing with my
plastic plant like I don't even have a
pet so yeah so I totally understand like
shyness but what happens is if you have
a dream if you keep saying I'm just an
ordinary person I will tell you what
Stan Lee said because I heard Stan Lee
talk about this very thing I watched him
live in an interview at Comic Expo when
he was still with us this incredible man
that had so much of an impact
um gave us the Marvel Universe along
with his creative colleagues and people
were were asking like how did you create
like why did you create what you created
and he
he um said something about I looked at
myself and I say you know there's a big
world out there there's billions of
people now I'm just another guy I'm an
I'm like an average ordinary guy so if I
love something if I love a character if
I love a story if I love something and
if you're an entrepreneur if I love a
product
surely there's a million people in this
billion people world billions and
millions surely there's a million people
that like it too because I'm like other
people
so if you're sitting there thinking I'm
average I'm this and that well actually
you're probably better positioned to
speak to a lot of people if that's the
case yeah
and and and that's why I always say
imposter syndrome actually points to the
fact that you are qualified
to go out there feeling like oh like I'm
not good enough yet most people who feel
that actually are way more qualified
than than not because you'll usually
have the so the dunning-kruger effect
is where when people first learn about
knowledge of a topic they feel like they
know everything right away and they're
like I could tell the world about it but
then immediately they drop down in their
knowledge and they're like wow I don't
know anything and so what I've found is
that most people when they get to that
point of I don't know anything is
actually when they've reached the
qualification to show people what they
know and to guide people and to lead
people at that level which is why you
don't need years of experience as an
expert to be a coach you don't need
years of experience as a course creator
and and and all these case studies to be
able to share with people what have you
learned along the way from your
experience
and if you just find somebody who's a
little bit further behind where you're
at
and help raise them up to a level of
where you're at and guide them while
you're simultaneously growing learning
new skills
learning about marketing defeating your
fears not letting your fears hold you
back
that's where I think I think the magic
happens is being willing to take that
risk everything's risky
there's no such thing as no risk
no matter what you do if we're looking
for okay what's the perfect moment where
I have where there's no risk and then
that's when I'm gonna strike that's a
fantasy that doesn't exist on Planet
Earth
I I will say that anything I've ever
done successfully I've done for the
first time I threw myself into like I
became a development executive and
having never been a development yeah me
too anything that I've been successful
at I did for the first time some people
might say well that's great for you guys
because like that's your personality but
my personality is I'm a planner or I'm a
I I need it all mapped out perfectly I
need to know that it's going to work I
need certainty I need a sure Foundation
I or I don't have time to waste for it
not to work out
well that's that's a hard one too
because I think that um persistence
obviously pays I've seen that time and
time again I mean I I know an actor who
uh for example was I ran into him we
hadn't seen each other in a while he was
upset because he'd gotten all these
auditions and callbacks and wasn't
booking anything and
um I I gave him the hang in their speech
right nothing feels like he was doing
landscaping here's this huge Talent you
know nobody no a huge Talent nobody
knows about and you have to sometimes
look at yourself and go maybe I am a
talent that nobody knows about because
I'm not actually letting myself know
about it yes you know right because life
is life is audition dress rehearsal
performance right but if you never allow
yourself to get to the audition because
you don't believe you're good enough
um it's it's tragic a little bit for me
because I hate seeing people give up on
themselves before they've even tried so
this person tried and tried and tried it
wasn't working it wasn't working and I
had to you know part of being a dream
facilitator part of being a coach is
reminding people that who they are is is
not what they have already achieved it's
what they're what it's what they're
attempting to do it's their action yes
right so that that's who they are it's
how they show up that that's who they
are and if they're having a gap between
uh actually showing up for for the
audition or the presentation I mean I've
helped people do presentations I've
helped people
um you know sort of pitch whether it's
in Hollywood or a boardroom it's
actually the emotions are exactly the
same that's true you know and people
yeah and I think and I learn a lot from
you actually about just showing up as
you are without without the fear of
being perfect without the fear of making
the wrong impression because we all at
some point or another make the wrong
impression who cares if you do who cares
and who cares and also like as much as
all these things have really high stakes
sometimes like I've pitched for
multi-million dollar projects and all
that stuff was was I perfect no I have
care that I can't control I have like
you know I don't have the perfect white
American ultra bright smile like there's
lots of things about me where I walk in
and I feel so uncomfortable comfortable
and I'm like oh my God I'm around people
again right and as much as I love people
um being on the spot being like having
my performance judged or anything like
that is actually so terrifying and but
yet what I find is if you figure out
what you love about what you're doing
because it's not actually even about you
it's about the love of what you're doing
and if you're able to connect with the
love of what you're doing and what
you're giving that's where you're coming
from and that's what you're speaking to
not whether you're worth being in that
room yeah that's good so I want to make
this practical for everybody we talk
about
um in our coaching program the six steps
for people to work through finding their
Niche starting to write their offer copy
create an offer do a live Zoom call
attract your uh Target client to that a
lot of what you just talked about
because real practically people get
stuck even picking their Niche because
they don't want to be the wrong Niche
they don't want it to be a wrong Niche
now they wasted their time now they put
something out there and it didn't work
out and so they would they they
would rather sit on the sidelines and
say man as soon as I pick my Niche then
I'll start to move forward I got a
message this morning from a lady who
literally word for word pretty much said
that Jeremiah as soon as I pick my Niche
I'm going to join your coaching program
she's been saying that for a year to me
she's been staying as soon as I pick my
Niche I'll join your coaching program
for and I and and and and I laugh but I
also want to have compassion for that
person because it's like
that's not working and I think if we
look at that like that
but that was that's trained Behavior
that's learned behavior
I'm laughing because it's so familiar
like yeah right it's familiar with me
I'm not laughing at them I'm laughing at
myself yeah it's so familiar right so
check this out yeah I I was supposed to
do the the LLC paperwork to move my
company from Arizona to Texas I started
that process in July I just finished it
this week
but because literally I came up with the
like well I don't know how to do it well
it took me
so I contacted like four attorneys and
they're like we don't really do that
most people just do it themselves
literally I actually had attorneys just
tell me to do it myself
wow which is funny I'm like can't I hire
you no I don't really do that okay so I
actually tried to go to an attorney to
hire them to do it and they're just like
they're like you can figure it out and I
finally did and I and I did figure it
out and it was actually way easier than
I thought I was just overthinking the
whole process
well I'm the queen of overthinking like
if there was an Olympic sport called
overthinking I would be on the podium
I'd have dominated you come up with you
simulate in your brain the 20 ways that
it can go wrong and right yeah but I
think that's why that's why journaling
and creating like one thing that people
are afraid of they're afraid of the
story going bad
right like like if they picked the other
thing too I think you have to have a
compelling why and a compelling dream
right so somebody that oh that's good
that's really the key and by the way
that's how you write a screenplay or you
write a novel it's like your protagonist
has to have and you know you can have
more than one protagonist potentially
like an ensemble but each one has to
have a very compelling dream and uh
because if they don't have a compelling
dream they don't have a compelling
desire and and then what happens is
there's no investment right I I see I I
rarely ever talk about this which I
think you're landing on something as to
why sometimes I I never talk about this
side of it which is good so keep going
this is amazing well I think if you have
a compelling dream you're willing to do
anything you're willing to pick up the
sword and win the sword fight and you
know like I love or lose or lose and
then you're willing to lose because the
dream is bigger than losing yes exactly
I mean that's a beautiful so beautiful
way to put it and speaking of losing
like I took um I took three and a half
years to write my Memoir of Panama
because I believe so deeply in craft and
the beauty of the words and how
important it had to be and somebody came
up to me and said it's a memoir you
already know what happens why is it
taking so long
right so from so from that perspective
like I was losing every single day that
it wasn't getting done that people were
thinking why is this girl taking so long
to write a one Memoir yeah so what
happens is like the story that I tell
the story that we tell about ourselves
is has to be a big enough dream I got
the Memoir done I got it out but when I
got it out I was proud of what I created
right so I had a compelling literary art
dream for lack of a better term but but
the point is and I broke I wrote through
a broken arm and I wrote through so many
different things because my dream was so
compelling because English is not my
first language I fell in love with that
language
um and when and I couldn't tell by
talking with you well I can't I came to
Canada when I was five but the thing is
the plan I'm trying to make is like for
me it was so much more than just
plunking words on the page there was a
much bigger and deeper compelling dream
in the creation of that if someone's
saying I just got to pick my Niche they
may have three other dreams oh I need to
be there for my kids I need to oh you
know I actually those dreams are more
important yeah those dreams that's great
that's amazing they just I don't want to
shame anybody out of that yeah they just
have to be aware in fact they should be
celebrating oh I actually have other
dreams yes but if you're honest about
what their their real dream is that's a
you know that's a huge part of it and
that does also play into screenwriting
and all that because a lot of times what
happens is your character along the way
discovers that oh maybe the dream that I
had like oftentimes too and those are
the best stories too those are often
such deeper meaning stories like I mean
even if you look at Skywalker Luke
Skywalker he wants to you know save the
world and and save the planet and all
that stuff but he's an orphan
and in a big deal way when he discovers
who his sister is when he discovers who
his family really is that's such a huge
and he creates a family with his friends
exactly right because really deep down
what he was missing was family wow and
that's the core of that's the core of
the whole
hero's journey of Star Wars
yeah yeah and so I think the what we're
getting into is that being able to
articulate what your core dream actually
is
and seeing yourself as the hero of that
core dream is going to make you a lot
more effective in achieving it I think
for me it's funny like sometimes I'm
like I don't want to like tell people
this core dream on my part here's what I
love about podcasts like this I'm I'm
super get to be super vulnerable in a
way that I don't normally get to like in
a coaching interaction or when I'm just
monologuing
um and so like one of my Big Dreams
really is like
like I want history books to have my
name in it
like like people in the future to know
who I am
and and and for what I'm not sure
but I know that like the trajectory that
I'm headed
even if that's not the case the the
people that I've worked with I know
history will write about and the people
that I impact and I know that I'm headed
like in that direction and everything
that I do is really sort of working in
that way and I and I see
art and storytelling and video games and
Technology converging around that as my
big dream
um but right now in this season it's I
want to find a thousand coaches
and course graders and help them become
multi-millionaires
because I know how to do that and and
like I don't feel like there's very many
people that do what I do
that coach other coaches and course
creators that
have that level of confidence in their
ability to create other millionaire
coaches
and so I'm excited to like just I want
to find those thousand people that are
going to become Millionaires and help
them reach that level help them make
over 83 333 dollars a month consistently
for 12 months at a time because that's
all that a million dollars is if you
actually break it down 12 months at a
time it's 83
333 dollars a month
times 12 equals 1 million that's a
thousand people paying you a thousand
dollars in one year
that's 500 people paying you two
thousand dollars in one year
and when you really break it down and
simplify it to that level and then you
take what you just shared what is the
real dream what is that real reason well
for for me
um
again I look at I I want a life that my
children can take this vision and stand
on top of and I look at what my mom is
doing that was a big part of her vision
as well is a life for her children to
stand on her shoulders and so I see this
as even like a generational dream that
goes to my grandchildren and
great-grandchildren and I don't know
what they're going to accomplish
but
and I even get choked up because my my
first son is is
going to be born
I don't know what he's gonna do
but I know that if I pour into him these
these lessons
that
he can accomplish anything he dreams of
and imagines and to go out there and
take a risk and experiment and just try
things out and not be afraid of what
happens
and and being really clear on what his
vision is and his vision doesn't have to
be what my vision is it can be
completely different like like he could
look back at this episode you know and
and hear that
and maybe remind me if I ever go off
track and become overbearing towards
what my vision for his life is right as
a parent because I feel like that ends
up naturally happening is happening as
parents
and so here's what I would ask you
is for the people listening to this
podcast right now
maybe they've never dreamed or actually
had a vision or they don't know what
their dream is
how can they start to identify it
well you know it's really interesting uh
that you asked that of a writer that is
a discovery writer because I'm actually
not an outline writer
I sit down and I just start writing yeah
and I find and I discover it as I go
yeah and it's an incredible thrill when
I get to a point where I go oh that's
what the character really dreams of
that's what they really want that's what
Their Fear is I might have a only a
vague idea when I start 475 Pages later
I know yes
if you don't know then you're actually
in sometimes even a better position
because you're not afraid of the unknown
because you don't know right so I know
that I know that we all we all want
certainty we all want safety we all want
security I totally get that yeah it's a
natural human thing it's a natural human
thing but so is curiosity yes and and
that's another like one of the number
one thing about storytelling is what's
going to happen next what's going to
happen next yes when I sit down to write
I don't know I only have a kind of vague
sense I might have a sense of what
roughly where it's going but I I don't
know what next line I don't know what
next action my character is going to
take and so if you fall in love with
Discovery if you fall in love with this
idea that you know you can look at it
either scientifically I get to
experiment and see if I blow up the lab
or not
right and it's okay to blow up the left
it's okay or or you can look at it from
a storytelling perspective I'm on a
treasure hunt and I don't know what's
around the corner am I going to find the
next clue yeah and if you if you allow
yourself
to look out onto the world and instead
of seeing all of the potential pitfalls
and all of those if you recognize that
that whatever you're aiming for even if
your dream is going to grow change get
bigger you know your Niche is going to
change whatever it's it's how you grow
as a person that is the Legacy that you
take with you when you go you see
because we may not be able to take money
we leave money we leave and there's
right I have huge respect for cohesive
families because I my family couldn't
sustain that for many reasons I'm a
child of divorce single parent all of
that stuff so when I see when I see a
provider especially a man that's able to
show up for his family like it really
touches my heart because my when I
didn't grow up in a family like that
either yeah and I think so but when I
lost my mom
um one of the things that struck me so
powerfully was her Legacy was her
behavior and you know she was a good
person she was a caring woman she had a
dream to take care of kids and when the
providing support like the co-provider
was taken away and it was all on her
shoulders she stepped up my your mother
my mother had a small dream just I just
went home and my kids to be okay and put
food on the table but she's crazy like a
soldier for that amazing like you're
yeah like you're hearing me like I got
like Elon Musk level dreams but like
hear me out like
no dream is too small like or
insignificant exactly that's your dream
like amazing like own that and and
create it exactly you're still the hero
though of your own story in that dream
you know I don't I know someone who's
you know with her husband raised four
kids had a cafe and you know saved my
sanity when I was writing my first book
let me in early before anybody else so I
could just you know start to write
eventually sold it retired now has grand
kids
has the best Christmas party and
Hanukkah party of anybody in the in the
world and she just fills my heart with
joy every time I even think about her
you know we are all contributors yes we
are all Dream Makers all the time in
everything and every life we touch and
it's all a legacy all of it's a legacy I
love this I love this conversation I'm
going to refer back to this to a lot of
people to listen to because this goes
into what we teach in our in our
coaching program a huge part of it what
you said about making it whether it be
you blow up the lab or or a treasure
hunt the way that I see for coaches and
course creators to be successful is
you're on a treasure hunt and the
treasure is inside of the minds of your
PR of your prospective coaching clients
but you haven't uncovered yet what their
deepest desires are and so you can't
uncover it simply by sitting on a couch
and writing it in a notepad or mapping
it out so that's why most people who set
out to build a coaching business they
spend six months to a year mapping out
their Niche mapping out their program
and it flops and they don't succeed when
you actually need to to create an offer
when we talk about an offer it's the
offers that we use are usually live Zoom
calls where we invite people to join us
and then I share to that group of people
about a topic that solves a problem for
them
but there's a but there's an ulterior
motive behind doing that and I'm even
learning I need to teach it as that
there really is an ulterior motive
behind doing that the ulterior motive is
entirely this I want to create an
opportunity to listen to people's
desires and to find that treasure that's
inside their mind
and so if they can tell you what that is
how do they tell you
you I put a survey at the beginning of
the the free training I invite them to
what's your biggest struggle as it
relates to the topic of the live event
that we're doing what would you like to
learn from me and people
tell me what those things are so now
then I document out all of those answers
and then I build my entire coaching
program and offers around what I didn't
know on the treasure hunt inside of
people's minds that they now offered up
for free in exchange for the value that
I'm delivering so that's what's really
cool is it's a value exchange a lot of
people see their offers as okay I'm
delivering value for their email address
I take it a step further I'm delivering
value to get the feedback from them
because I'm doing this specifically to
hear from
people who may or may not be my target
client what are they struggling with
what are their deepest desires and what
would a solution to that look like I
want to know the dreams and desires of
those that I'm coaching and so if you're
a coach if you're a course creator
creating live Zoom events opportunities
where you can gather people in front of
you for the purpose of getting inside of
their mind and asking okay what is your
deepest struggle what would you like to
learn what are you dealing with like
what is stopping you
then that data that's the gold right
there the treasure that then I take that
into our AI copywriting tools Jasper AI
chat GPT Jasper just added Jasper chat
this week which is actually a better
version of chat GPT inside of Jasper
trained on what they do and so and it's
it's also free for a limited time right
now for people that are using Jasper to
use I take the gold that I've sort of
I'm like sifting gold I see myself as a
prospector sifting gold and what's in it
is I'm sifting sifting sifting a lot of
it is dirt but there's gold from those
answers what that what are they
struggling with what are the questions
they ask and then the AI identifies the
gold and creates offers for me off of
that and so I you know I don't have even
have to think that hard about well what
should I coach on well what should my
Niche be because you want to start with
sort of a vague Niche idea but then
create an opportunity for your audio
chance to tell you what the real Niche
is and your audience gives you the
answer when you create an opportunity
for them to feel safe to be vulnerable
with you to tell you what they're
struggling with most people I found over
the last four years I wasn't creating a
safe space for people to tell me what
they were struggling with
I was I was truthfully I was demanding
people tell me what they were struggling
with and nobody would and I was getting
really frustrated because I'm like
join me for a live for a free 15-minute
call nobody was scheduling calls with me
I'm like I'm literally offering coaching
I built eight figure coaching businesses
I'm letting you do a call with me for
free why are you not taking these calls
I was getting pissed off at my audience
about it until I realized okay you're
not creating a safe space for people to
even tell you their problems
and so I had to look internally and to
how can I actually make this a safe
space to where they feel like okay I'm
not going to get hurt or taken advantage
of by sharing these problems and then
that's what we create our our offers
around I did Growing your email list the
fun way get more paid clients launch
your six figure coaching offer so this
the past two weeks I've created uh eight
instances where people have verbally
told me on a q a what their problems are
and now I'm going back to the drawing
board with my Ai and building out my
next three to five offers
off of the words that they gave me
and so that's such a huge part of the
process that we teach that we coach on
that we help people with is how do you
sift that goal how do you find that gold
and go on a treasure hunt and find what
is the one it could be one line it could
be one sentence that somebody says oh
I'd like to learn this from Jeremiah or
I'm struggling with this I identified a
lot of people really need help with
their funnels I didn't teach anything on
funnels for four years I'm like you can
find so much free training on funnels
everywhere
but people kept coming to me asking me
to teach funnels and now we're starting
to see the results of it as I've been
teaching that and even teaching
something I didn't want to teach on
but because people wanted me to share it
from my perspective they're now getting
results because that's actually me
humbling myself a little bit saying okay
I don't want to teach on this but people
are asking for it constantly I'm going
to give them what they want and now the
gold is coming out we're having clients
making tens of thousands of dollars with
their offers in the coaching program
and so that's that's just what's
incredible and you're you're in that
program as well Lila
um Leela sorry actually I have Lila Lila
it's okay I answered it both because it
actually is pronounced differently in
different countries so yeah yeah yeah
it's totally cool I love everything that
you're saying it's a lot to do with like
my one of my favorite authors Janet
Ivanovic
who wrote One for the Money um and it
became a film with Katherine Heigl and
she she writes the famous Stephanie Plum
series and she spent the first 10 years
of her life only hearing no no no no no
no no no no no go away she ended up she
started with like this big of a box for
her rejections and by the time she was
done it was a shirt box and she ended up
uh giving up completely after 10 years
no no no no no no could just gave up
completely burned her rejection letters
outside on her stoop crying
what and and went and became a secretary
um or actually I think it was more she
worked in insurance but it was kind of
like a tempting she talks about you know
borrowing a suit and going to work in
office and four months into it she was
out with one of her children to like you
know taking them skating or swimming or
something and her husband and her son
um she was with her daughter her husband
her son came to her put their arms
around her and said your editor called
and what had happened was
one of the very last things she wrote
was a romance novel in a popular genre
because she had not been listening to
what people really wanted to read she
had not been hearing what her Talent was
really meant to do because deep down she
wanted to be a popular entertaining fun
Happy author but she was writing what
she thought and I listen I've made the
same mistake myself but it's not really
a mistake because we're always learning
I blew up the lab the lab blew up and
now I'm learning how to make a nicer lab
yeah it's that thing where you want to
give something like I wanted to give
literary because the English language
has given me so much freedom and
communication and I love it so deeply so
I wanted to give this big you know deep
Memoir only to realize when the Memoir
was done oh wait I'm not famous
who's actually going to want to read
their Memoir of somebody they've never
heard of them before and as much as I
you know have have they will when you
become famous well yes and and more
power to them and it's very vulnerable
it's very real it's very honest Memoir
but the point being when I was done I
realized oh
what and and the funny thing was people
sometimes think it's chicklet because
it's written in a very entertaining way
but what I realized was wait a minute
have I really heard the real dream
my real dream is that I want to make
people laugh and I want to uplift them
and I want to tell sweeping beautiful
romantic but also mythical stories like
what's my real dream and and if you
don't I wouldn't have really
you know as much as I as much as I um
I'm starting to get a much better sense
of who I am part of what happened when
you're talking about I didn't create a
safe space all you're really talking
about is getting to the point where
you know what question to ask you create
a beautiful space for to ask the
question where people see feel safe to
answer and then you listen and hear yep
the answer every single person listening
to this podcast right now has that skill
every single person if they want to 100
ask you know
um what's your struggle with this what's
your dream for this it's actually one of
the most natural human skills that we
all possess but sometimes we walk away
from because of Life beliefs experiences
we learn it as kids
like we care if somebody's struggling we
care if somebody wants you know wants
something like we care and I think what
happens is we get so caught up in
performance anxiety right and perform as
coach and I must like when I'm on this
um you know when I'm in this um five-day
challenge I've given I must you know be
the lecturer the leader the give it my
all the coaching is the exact opposite
it's it's the sharing hearing caring
listening yes it's really holding that
that space and I've seen the difference
when when a coach is just caught up in
their own
um I'm great on wonderful monologuing
monologue and and
as opposed to the way you coach which is
a narcissistic monologuing is what I
like to call it yeah and they can be
really like some people can be really
they can be really successful doing that
too yeah that's their that you know
that's their thing that's their natural
thing but I ask for the exception not
the rule
well what I find that I love about your
coaching style is it's very authentic
it's very present you're when you share
from your authentic play itself it's to
to give the rest of us permission to
realize that we don't have to be perfect
to take steps and be successful we don't
actually need to know what our Niche is
perfectly before we take action and
that's something that you've helped me
get over a lot because
um
you know I I mean I'm in an industry
where criticism criticism criticism
criticism like that is I eat criticism
for breakfast lunch dinner like I mean
that's just that's just such a common
thing if you're in the entertainment
business and I remember you know I
remember being in theater school and one
of my my professors said imagine you're
a pharmacist and every time you write a
prescription there's an audience waiting
to judge you
because that's that's what being in the
Arts like I started you know and if
if I wasn't being judged if I even
behind the scenes judgment judgment
judgment oh why that line you know why
did you make a character that did this
why did you like judgment judgment
judgment and so you have to you you what
happens is because like what we're
really talking about at the end of the
day
is people having courage
yes people having courage to take action
even when they don't know
exactly their perfect Niche they don't
even mean you may not even know what
your actual dream is until you get it
and here's a really good idea on that
the courage to not have to be
in your final form
the courage to not have to be yeah
an original right away meaning like I
think a lot of people wait until they're
like okay well I'm so different
from everybody else or what could I do
because
everybody else is already doing this I'm
not I'm not original enough I hear that
as a reason for people too it's okay
to be kind of a combo of like five or
six different niches out there that
you've seen in the beginning and it will
morph into your originalness
well that's that's what improvisation
like if any I really suggest like if
anyone's really struggling with putting
themselves out because they have to have
it everything perfect take an improv
class yep you know I was like I was
taking Second City improv classes
um because I because I wanted to do that
as my part of my creativity but I saw
people with sales people I saw people
like you know um Executives taking those
classes because they're like I just want
to get out of my shell a little bit more
yeah I just like I just want to learn
how to be a little bit more spontaneous
because
um and then you'd have things throwing
at you and you'd have to like in that
moment come up with a line and sometimes
um that would help unlock people but I I
think the thing is like at the end of
the day
if you want if you're if your desire is
bigger then your desire to stay safe
that's when I think you really start
getting momentum like that's it yeah and
for me I just don't want to I just don't
want to live an unfulfilled life my mom
died quite young and I'm not too far
from from that time and I don't I just I
want to know that at the end of the day
I I actually did give it my all and I
showed up and I think that a lot like
I've heard the phrase in coaching earn
while you learn
because because if you have to be
perfect you're actually not actually
helping anyone like I was helping I was
19 20 23 spotting talent and saying go
for it like you know and and really
articulating to people like why why go
for it you know I I've been a I've been
doing organically and naturally dream
like facilitating people's dreams
organically and naturally way before I
had any success myself
because the human Spirit wants to not
just strive
the human Spirit doesn't want to always
be in striving it wants to cross the
finish line first it wants to get on the
gold Podium it wants to soar and be you
know have bigger and bigger dreams and
if you never take that step out that
front door yeah the problem is it's not
the problem isn't that you didn't
achieve problem is is that you stifled
yourself and you didn't grow
and so it really doesn't matter if if
the dream is big or small what matters
is that you let your dream just be
bigger than your dream of staying
comfortable and small mm-hmm
and I think that that's really again it
goes back to something that I say a lot
is actually owning the fact that you're
responsible for your actions each day
that that the actions that you take
aren't because of other people they
aren't because of environmental factors
they aren't because of what's happening
to you or what's happened to you now
what's happened to you might have
created certain beliefs what's happening
around you might be creating certain
circumstances that make it harder but
you're responsible for how do I make
decisions with all this going on rather
than we think okay as soon as all of
this trouble around me is gone then I
can be successful as soon as all this
chaos is gone as soon as things are in
order when the truth is that the magic
of Storytelling coaching building a
business happens inside of
uncertainty and chaos and not having it
all planned out that that it only comes
together where it looks like it was put
together
by starting from that sort of hurricane
of energy and and really finding your
own peace in the middle of the hurricane
to start to create
well I think if you knew okay so I have
heating Plumbing all kinds of issues
going on my building actually went down
went dark
um Christmas Day last year
so I'm coming up to that traumatic
moment where I will my wife almost got
T-boned an hour ago oh my God yeah and
I'm surrounded by boxers by now although
your wife like thank God she's okay
she's fine but yeah it was like oh my
gosh yeah and here I am right yeah we
are and this is spontaneous and
unplanned like in case nobody realizes
that
um but I think that but that getting to
a point where you can jump on a podcast
spontaneously and unplanned like I when
I started my podcast
um it's um and it's you know it's not
it's still a you know developing podcast
but when I started it was in the midst
of the pandemic because somebody
speaking to this great lessons in that
well thank you that's so kind and um I
really wanted to help people I mean
they're genius so I called them into
genius but it also came out of listening
to someone that I knew had worked so
hard to get BMA one of my fellow m8ers
for lack of a better terms uh because we
got our ma novel writing and she was
saying oh it's the pandemic my kids are
home I have to help them on this side I
don't know if I'm going to get my novel
done and I I just my heart broke a
little
because she was in the midst of chaos
and she couldn't find even 10 minutes to
give herself the gift of the thing that
she actually deeply wanted that she just
worked to do which was to spend time
with her novel it and the thing is like
even if she just stares at a blank page
spending 10 minutes yeah reaffirming
something deeply beautiful about
yourself is important and so I started
my podcast in the midst of my own chaos
with no plan and not knowing where it
was going to go but I just
I just had desire and you know I've
heard it said like you don't need money
you don't need contacts you don't need
there's so many things you don't need as
much as you need desire yep
yep
and desire desire isn't something that
your coach is going to give you
desire isn't even something you're gonna
pick up off of a podcast that's the
inner work that's the responsibility
that like you could listen to a podcast
like this I believe that there are
people that are listening to this
podcast right now they're listing this
recording and it's going to be a massive
breakthrough in their life but I also
know that there are people who are going
to listen to this and they're not going
to do anything with it and they're going
to be in the same place a year from now
that's the personal choice that we all
have the personal responsibility are you
going to take a message like this
do something with it or are you going to
keep living life the same way that you
have the last three to five years and I
think that that's the choice that we all
have to make every single day every
single month every single week I take a
look at okay what's a habit that I've
been dealing with for 20 years what's a
habit that I've been dealing with for 10
years for five years what's a habit that
I picked up
two years ago that is no longer serving
me anymore what's a habit that I picked
up six months ago and I'm looking at
certain habits and I'm saying are these
serving me for my ultimate vision and
goal
one of the big ones for me is
when people
come at me and get nasty and accuse me
of things
it really shuts me down emotionally
but I'm realizing where I am going with
my goals that's only going to get worse
and so I need to work on the inner work
of okay how do I not literally
completely shut down freeze and and and
truthfully it's it's about healing
trauma and I'm and that's what I'm
working with my therapist on is that
that shutdown that I have where I
literally go from like who you see here
to like just wanting to curl in a ball
for no reason whatsoever other than
somebody said something mean to me
online
laughs I'm so glad you brought that up I
I'm so so glad you brought that up
because I think that that people are so
afraid of putting themselves out there
even in small ways let alone online
where you feel exposed and the the
reality is this the things that make us
feel shame is the idea that the worst
thing said about us is true and so when
we're vilified when we're vilified it
just brings us back to to this place of
questioning our very right to exist and
because the biggest the biggest thing
like whether someone takes action or
doesn't take action or whatever but the
biggest thing I hope people take from
this today is your self-perception yes
is a hundred percent in your power yes
and that is the key to everything your
self-perception is 100 your power that's
it and and to be willing to you yeah be
willing to take responsibility for that
is a big thing that's not to say you
won't get hurt let's not just say you
won't feel triggered that's not to say
you won't end up in a ball
on the couch certainly I mean gosh I
mean I have I told you stories oh my
goodness yeah yesterday I literally was
like I had a thought I'm like Can Am I
helping anybody
like
today you're talking to someone that
you've helped enormously in a very short
period of time yeah right we all have
that we all have that we all deal with
it but I want to talk about imposter
syndrome for a moment because I think
you just you just nailed what I think
imposter syndrome is because
I don't believe in imposter syndrome I
don't think anyone actually has what's
called imposter syndrome what I actually
think is the world is mean and hard
sometimes yeah right and it likes to lie
to you and convince you that you're not
good enough it likes to throw these
daggers at you and say and say you know
Jeremiah you should be out there Leela
who do you think you are I I I feel like
it's impossible for anybody no matter
how great and big and talented and Elon
Musk and who knows and whatever Angelina
Jolie everybody it's impossible for
anyone to get a breath and feel like I
have the right to to my own greatness to
my own inherent greatness because
there's always somebody waiting in the
wings to try to take it take you down so
you don't have imposter syndrome we just
live in a world that can sometimes be
hostile and and that's why surrounding
yourself with love whether it's family
or friends or Community whatever you
find it is so is so critically important
that one creating your safety yeah and
that
that safe place for me at six o'clock in
the morning 6 15 dark winter night minus
20 but I could quietly go into the cafe
before anybody was there and she would
make me my very first you know
espresso of the day
she created this idea of what safety
feels like in my mind in a way that I
had never been able to birth an entire
book before
but she would not have offered that if I
hadn't started writing the book before I
even met her
right like that that safe space didn't
arrive until I had already put out what
I was doing and so many people are
waiting for their safe space to arrive
wait until they have it or they feel it
before they start when in fact usually
that safety that we're looking for
materializes by us doing the work by us
stepping out in a risky place
it's such a paradox but I think it's
because we're not here to just
to just be we're here we're here to grow
as Souls it's a soul Journey that's the
Hero Journey like when I talk about the
Hero Journey the the author Journey the
protagonist Journey like when I talk
about that Hero Journey I'm really
actually speaking about the human soul
Journey yeah because that is what we
human beings have have deeply found
meaning in and have been fascinated by
from like the dawn of time so the moment
we could tell stories the moment we
could cave paint the moment we could act
out the hunt the moment we could tell
those stories we elevated our experience
into into something that imprints on our
soul yeah I believe that's what we take
with us I we may be leaving beautiful
material things for the people that we
love because so they could have more
opportunity to Mint their genius and
live their full potential but what we
take with us is what we learned how we
loved how we grew
um
that's so good I love that this has been
such a great conversation with you thank
you so much for being here and and how
can people plug in with you and learn
more about what you're doing
sure well I have my podcast it's called
minted genius m-i-n-t-e-d genius withly
Lizzy Rose I also have my Lila Zero's
website awesome and um people like I
just have for right now I just have this
you know Gmail from into genius because
we're launching and lots of things are
happening so if somebody wants to reach
me even by email it's meant to genius
gmail.com and
um yeah I love let's simple like this is
another thing like just really proving
you can put yourself out there even with
a Gmail address you do not totally if
somebody I know is making 10K a month as
a coach with a Gmail address so yeah you
know just the the courage to just be who
you are where you are and also the
honesty of like telling people right now
I'm surrounded by boxes and I have a
Gmail address
and yeah
I dream big for myself and for others
and so I feel like at the end of the day
we just we just show up as we are and we
we build from there and
um when you said I like create Magic
well it's because I see the hugest
possibility even in the tiny seat I
already see the tree I already see you
know what what can blossom and grow and
I really you you help give me courage I
mean you're you've changed me so much
more than I can even possibly say in
such a short period of time to have the
courage to take action which is what
ends awesome I'm so glad that really
helped you and you do it by example you
don't just do it by by lecturing you
actually do it by doing it yourself as
well and I completely admire you for
that Jeremiah that's something huge to
learn just as coaches course creators
what we do by example the people that we
coach will follow
and so
in the beginning you mentioned
halfway through this people taking
Improv
I didn't take improv classes but I
committed to making one live video a day
unscripted unedited for a year straight
and I just recorded a 10 minute talk and
I did a podcast and that got me to where
I felt really comfortable just flowing
and talking and speaking by actually
doing that behavior and doing the work
and I really struggle with it I used to
sweat bullets before I would press
record every single time now I don't
because I was able to really rewire my
brain rewire my behavior to actually
rock at improv speaking where I
couldn't public speak for anything to
save my life five years ago at all I
would just stutter and stop and stall
and couldn't keep my thoughts in order
or anything but it was the activity of
putting myself out there even
imperfectly even knowing okay I could be
better I could do better
but not waiting to be better or do
better to actually put myself out there
that's what's helped our business grow
and helped our business create the kind
of impact that it's having today and so
thank you just for being a part of this
community thanks for your encouragement
to everybody I'm so glad that that
you're here
um and for everybody who's listening to
this if this is if this has helped you
if you have questions again Reach Out
comment on some of my posts on social
media comment on this video on YouTube
and I'd love to connect with you I'd
love to talk with you if there's an area
where you're stuck at
I'd love to hear like what do you need
help with what are you struggling with
what is this what did this bring up in
you you know by the way me saying that
is an example of my feedback loop
because if I can if I can hear from
people what they're struggling with I
can create better podcasts I can design
better tools and resources for people
that are free to help people which is
cool so you're you're as listeners are a
part of that by the feedback which is
awesome as well if this episode has
helped you and you know somebody else
that will help don't keep it to yourself
share the podcast with somebody else let
this message get out there to more
people
we need your help for that and so thank
you Leela for being here thank you to
the listeners grow your life everybody
and we'll talk soon have a good one
[Applause]